Suraya Clemens

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

www.suraya.xyz surayaclemens@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/suraya-clemens github.com/surayaclemens

PROFILE

I see web development as a tool to combine my love of creating cool things with my responsibility to work towards a more equitable future, and seek engagements that prioritize accessibility & inclusivity along with innovation.

Outside my work in the tech sector, my background in linguistics provided me with practical experience in both logical and humanist thinking, and my academic accomplishments demonstrate that I execute top quality work.

Complementing these hard skills is my extensive experience in customer service, which cultivated my ability to identify and meet interpersonal needs, and form lasting positive relationships.

My colleagues know me as an excellent communicator, initiative-taker, thorough problem solver, and big fan of jokes.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React, Flutter, Dart, Express, Node, Firebase, SQL, REST APIs, DOM APIs, User Auth, OAuth, Heroku, Git, GitHub, Figma, Jira, Agile Methodology

EXPERIENCE

Comprehensive list on LinkedIn

Full-stack Developer, Front-end Lead | Cedulify Inc.

AUG 2022 - Present, REMOTE/MONTREAL, QC

- Developed and maintained dynamic & responsive web application using Angular, TypeScript, SCSS, Node.js, Firebase
- Supported mobile developer with tasks in Flutter and Dart
- Oversaw client-side of the app: directed design, provided wireframes and hi-fi mockups, acted as point person for front-end development and communicator between devs and stakeholders
- Utilized Git version control system to manage code repositories
- Actively participated in code reviews, design reviews, and discussions on architecture; received and provided constructive feedback from/to peers to ensure high code quality and best practices
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs to facilitate data exchange between the frontend and backend systems
- Integrated third-party APIs such as Stripe and Facebook Conversions
- Collaborated closely with product leads, designers and other developers from identifying needs, to ideation, to design, to technical specifications and actionable tasks
- Facilitated Agile development processes, leading daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and reviews
- Thrived in a fast-paced startup environment, effectively multitasking and adapting rapidly changing business conditions and priorities

Research Assistant | Syrians Learning English for Employment in Canada (SLEEC), University of Victoria

SEP 2021 - APR 2022, VICTORIA, BC

- Planned and conducted academic study within SLEEC pilot program to inform the language-learning experience of refugees and newcomers to Canada
- Executed through survey composition, literature review, participant interviews, qualitative content analysis, synthesis of findings + graphic design for presentation, public speaking

Web Master | Van Brothers Forming Ltd. (Contract)

DEC 2020 - MAR 2021, REMOTE/VANCOUVER, BC

- Re-designed and re-branded the company's existing marketing site to meet industry standards and attract bigger clients
- Exceeded stakeholder goals by refining information architecture, improving UX, and modernizing UI
- Produced site on CMS and migrated to company's domain

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development

JUL 2022, VANCOUVER, CA

University of Victoria | Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics

APR 2022, VICTORIA, CA

• GPA 4.0, Undergraduate Research Award, President's Scholarship

PROJECTS

- Morphology: Gamified learning for heritage & indigenous language revitalization (Next.js, Firebase)
- Alatúlie: English to Elvish translator (React, JS, SCSS, Node.js)